Can two friends sleep together and still love each other in the morning?
When Harry Met Sally... is a comedy, romance, drama film directed by Rob Reiner.
Sex always gets in the way of friendships between men and women.
At least, that's what Harry Burns believes.
So when Harry meets Sally Albright and a deep friendship blossoms between them,
Harry's determined not to let his attraction to Sally destroy it.
But when a night of weakness ends in a morning of panic, can the pair avoid succumbing to Harry's fears
by remaining friends and admitting they just might be the perfect match for each other?
Harry Burns, played by Billy Crystal.
Sally Albright, played by Meg Ryan.
Marie, played by Carrie Fisher.
Jess, played by Bruno Kirby.
Joe, played by Steven Ford.
Alice, played by Lisa Jane Persky.
When Harry Met Sally...
is a 1989 American romantic comedy film directed by
Rob Reiner and written by Nora Ephron.
Starring Billy Crystal, Meg Ryan, Carrie Fisher, and Bruno Kirby, it follows the title characters from the time they meet in Chicago and share a drive to New York City through twelve
years of chance encounters in New York, and addresses the question "Can men and women ever just be friends?"
Ideas for the film began when Reiner and Penny Marshall divorced.
An interview Ephron conducted with Reiner provided the basis for
Harry; Sally was based on Ephron and some of her friends.
Crystal came on board and made his own contributions to the screenplay.
Ephron supplied the structure of the film with much of the dialogue based
on the real-life friendship between Reiner and Crystal.
The soundtrack consists of standards from Harry Connick Jr., with a
big band and orchestra arranged by Marc Shaiman.
For his work on the soundtrack, Connick won his first Grammy
Award for Best Jazz Male Vocal Performance.
Columbia Pictures released When Harry Met Sally in selected cities, letting word of
mouth generate interest, before gradually expanding distribution.
The film grossed $92.8 million in North America, and
was released to critical acclaim.
Ephron received the BAFTA Award for Best Original Screenplay, as well as
nominations for the Academy Award, WGA Award and Golden Globe.
The film is ranked 23rd on AFI's 100 Years...
100 Laughs list of the top comedy films in American cinema and
number 60 on Bravo's "100 Funniest Movies".
In early 2004, the film was adapted for the stage in a
production starring Luke Perry and Alyson Hannigan.
In 2022, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of new year's eve, new york city,
friendship, husband wife relationship, orgasm.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.